Aswin Baskaran

UX/UI Designer I aswinbaskaran.com I aswin.rbaskaran@gmail.com

I'm Aswin, a designer with supplemental technical skills. Having mostly worked for community based application in Aotearoa New Zealand, my strength is in designing web and mobile apps. I'm known for finding simple solutions for complex problems. What sets me apart as a designer is my functionality first stance, considering not only usability but also optimisation, accessibility and security.

Experience

Verizon Connect

Senior Experience Designer | Nov 2021 - Current

Working closely with our remotely based product team and the local engineering team to help ensure that the product requirements will meet user needs, and designing how best to implement them.

Tupay - Antocin Limited

Digital Designer | Feb 2021 - Current

Preparing and redesign a B2B website and app for the launch in October 2021. Collecting information about users and solving problems. Learned to use Figma jam. Working with the team of software developers and design team based in London to ensure the quality of the design and usably is on the highest level.

AM Creative software

UX/UI Designer I Oct 2020 - Jan 2021

Curating and building out AM creative software's Design System for company consumption. Designed various brand assets such as graphics, emails etc. for marketing and distribution purposes. User research and testing; promote and encourage user testing of your work throughout the design lifecycle.

Case Study

Thornton Green - Freelance (Auckland Based)

App Designer I Jun 2020 - Jul 2020

The client requested to refine the interface of the application and add a processing box to indicate the process of the application to verify the individual for approval to buy cars. App had a mechanic similar to tinder where you can swipe to like or dislike the cars. The information will be sent to Wishlist therefore users can check or purchase their favorite cars.

Case Study

The App Guys

UX/UI Designer I June 2020 - Aug 2020

Creating a design for accounting software and developing the document based on strategy, outlining the scope and sitemaps. Starting from low-fidelity mock-ups (wireframes) to high fidelity mock-ups (UI development phase) and finally prototyping the mock-ups.

Education

Media Design School

Bachelor of Creative Technologies Auckland, New Zealand Sep 2018 - Jun 2021

California Institute Of The Arts

UI/UX Specialization
California, United States (Remote)
Oct 2020 - Feb 2020

Achievements

- IBM Design Thinking Course Enterprise design
- SAP Design Thinking and Challenge Management
- Created first no-code app in Aotearoa (Bravo Studio) - <u>Case Study</u>

Skills

Jser interface	User experience
 Design sketching 	 Prototyping
 Design systems 	 Journey mapping
 Marketing assets 	 UX research
• IOS/ android	 Design sprint
 Website 	process
applications	 Design thinking
	process

Softwares

Userflow & Low-Fi

- JustinmindTimbleeFlowmappOverflow
- OverflowBalsamiq

Hi-Fi & Prototype

FigmaAdobe XDPhotoshopIllustratorInDesign